## MD SAIF SIDDIQUE RAYHAN

Software Engineer

West Rampura, Dhaka
(+880) 1676-449264
Saif.rafi07@gmail.com

saifsiddiquerayhan https://github.com/saifsiddiquee https://stackoverflow.com/users/10585447

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Passionate and highly motivated developer successful at building Android applications. Well-educated and poised with 4 years of expertise. Proficient in Java and Kotlin, with a focus on user-cantered design and intuitive navigation. Recently expanded my skillset to include 2 years of experience with Flutter, allowing me to create high-performing, visually stunning apps for both iOS and Android platforms.

# EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Jahangirnagar University M.Sc in CSE • 2021 CGPA: 3.76/4.00

American International University – Bangladesh B.Sc in CSE • 2018 CGPA: 3.47/4.00

# INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

- · Latest technologies
- · Jetpack Compose
- Photography
- · Competitive Gaming
- · Problem solving

#### **PUBLICATION**

Controlling Multimedia Player with Eye Gaze Using Webcam.

This application detects the eye gaze of a user sitting in front of a webcam. By tracking the eye, it can control multimedia player functionalities such as play, pause, fast forward, and back forward.

https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8644103

#### **ONLINE PORTFOLIO:**

saifsiddiquee.github.io/

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DECEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

 $BRAC\ IT\ Services\ Ltd.-\textit{Sr.}\ \textit{Software}\ Engineer$ 

Android | Flutter | Java | Kotlin | Dart | Jetpack

- Worked with the business team to prioritize the list of enhancements and new features for our Smart Microfinance android application.
- Worked with the UI designer to implement the new UI design with best practices for mobile devices.
- Integrated backend API service along with other services.
- Dynamic UI generation from JSON or backend API.
- Integrated the offline database (Room/SQLite) and experienced writing complex queries.
- Worked with the room database migration.
- Unit-testing code for robustness, including edge cases, usability, and general reliability.
- Rapidly developing in house applications.
- Consistent pairing with and mentoring junior engineers on the team.

FEBRUARY 2019 - OCTOBER 2020

## Royalty Bangladesh Inc. – Android Developer

Android | Java | Jetpack

- Designed and implemented the UI with best practices for all types of mobile devices.
- Integrated backend API service along with other services.
- Integrated payment gateway services.
- Interacted with other engineers to learn and spread best practices.
- Worked with documenting the existing code base.
- Maintained published applications and continuously integrated new features.
- Integrated analytics and crashlytics to identify the bugs and unexpected behaviours.

OCTOBER 2018 - JANUARY 2019

# Geeks'n'Technology Ltd. – *Programmer Intern* Android | Java | PHP | Laravel

- Interacted with other engineers to learn and spread best practices.
- Learned business logic and coding structure from the existing code base.
- Implemented the assigned feature and learned to debug.
- Worked with web technologies.
- Learned and practiced the android architecture and lifecycle components.

#### PROJECT ACCOMPLISHMENTS

#### **Smart PO**

BRAC microfinance Android application for Programme Organizer (PO)

- MVVM architecture.
- Device Registration with unique device Id.
- Fully offline capabilities with sync.
- Long running background task management with work-manager.
- Complex and optimized database queries.
- Dynamic UI generation form JSON.
- Notifications
- Remote config

#### Play Store:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.bracits.smartpo

#### **Roval Touch**

- A-share market Flutter application for retail stock brokerage
- Developed, tested and deployed mobile applications for both iOS and Android platforms using React Native.
- Utilized Firebase for user authentication and database management.
- Implemented push notifications and other features to improve user engagement.
- Worked with designers to ensure that the final product was visually pleasing and easy to use.

### Google Play Store:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.royalcapitalbd.apps.royalcapital

#### Apple App Store:

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/royaltouch/id1612836493?fbclid= IwAROS5GimGD6VjmLsBfGZWd0LNFNVN007CXvkU zDs1NwyhisZBSoecWjejmI

#### **Smart BM**

BRAC microfinance Android application for Branch Manager (BM)

- MVVM architecture.
- Device Registration with unique device Id.
- Combination of Online and Offline with manual and auto sync mechanism.
- Long running background task management with work-manager.
- Notifications
- Remote config

#### Play Store:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bracits.smartbm

#### Royalty - Discover offers, discounts & rewards.

A loyalty platform Android application with payment gateway

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details ?id=com.royalty.bd

#### **Royalty Merchant**

Merchant Android application for registered merchants

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details ?id=com.royaltybd.royaltybd\_merchant

#### **Royalty Sales Force**

Sales Android application for sales team of Royalty <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.royaltybd.royalty\_salesforce">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.royaltybd.royalty\_salesforce</a>

#### **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

- Excellent communication skills in both technical and non-technical discussions.
- Strong Java, Kotlin and Dart programming experience working in application development.
- Proven experience consuming RESTful ISON APIs.
- Experienced in working with android dependency injection Dagger 2.0 and Hilt.
- Practical knowledge of common data structures and software design practices.
- Skilled in Dart, with a strong understanding of the Flutter framework and its capabilities.